# **Khairy Ibrahem Mohamed**

Cairo, Egypt

# **Summary**

Senior System Administrator with experience in Virtualization with VMware vSphere, ESXi 7.0,6.0 VCenter Converter, SCCM, Active Directory Administration, Windows 2008\2012\2016\2022 server upgrade, File share migration, PowerShell, Microsoft Office365 and Odoo ERP expert with skills in system configuration and user support.

### **Education**

Bachelor of Management Information Technology

Higher Technological Institute 10 of Ramadan Cairo, Egypt | Graduated: 2016 | Grade: Good

# **Work Experience**

# **Senior System Administrator**

Durrat Al Rimal (4 branches), Saudi Arabia, Apr 2024 - Till Now

- Managed ERP modules (Inventory, Manufacturing, Sales, CRM, POS, HR), improving operational efficiency by 30%.
- Delivered comprehensive user training and support, achieving a 95% system adoption rate within three months by facilitating smooth onboarding and improving user proficiency.
- Streamlined data management processes by automating manual tasks, reducing workload by 40% and enhancing reporting accuracy and reliability.
- Administered and optimized VMware ESXi virtualized environments to ensure high availability and optimal performance.
- Managed network infrastructure including switches, firewalls, servers, and access points, maintaining 99.9% uptime.

### **Senior System Administrator**

### Abu Dhabi media corporation Egypt office, Cairo, May 2019 - Apr 2024

- Designed, installed, and configured enterprise servers, network devices, and firewalls, ensuring 99.9% uptime for internal and client-facing systems.
- Managed virtualization environments using VMware ESXi and Microsoft Hyper-V, improving resource utilization by 25%.
- Implemented and maintained SQL server, FortiGate firewalls, and Kaspersky security, reducing security incidents by 40%.
- Oversaw Qnap nas storage and Veeam backup and replication, achieving 100% data recovery success rate during tests.
- Administered enterprise-scale windows server platforms, active directory, office 365, group policy objects, and DNS, improving its service delivery time by 35%.
- Diagnosed and resolved complex Lan/wan and backbone infrastructure issues, reducing network downtime by 10%.

#### **System Administrator**

#### Sera Factory – EL-Obour City, March 2018 – May 2019

- Installed and configured Sophos XG Firewall and Kaspersky Security, enhancing endpoint protection coverage by 50%.
- Deployed and managed Windows Server 2008/2012/2016, DC, ADC, DNS, DHCP, File Share, WSUS, and Hyper-V, ensuring stable operations with 98% uptime.
- Configured and maintained Backup Exec and ERP database backups, achieving zero data loss across all recovery simulations.
- Monitored system performance and resolved hardware/software issues for servers, laptops, desktops, and printers, reducing IT support tickets by 20%.

## **IT Specialist**

#### Printex, Cairo, Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

- Installed and configured Sophos XG firewall and Kaspersky security, enhancing endpoint protection coverage by 50%.
- Deployed and managed windows server 2008/2012/2016, DC, ADC, DNS, DHCP, file share, WSUS, and Hyper-V, ensuring stable operations with 98% uptime.
- Configured and maintained backup exec and Erp database backups, achieving zero data loss across all recovery simulations.
- Monitored system performance and resolved hardware/software issues for servers, laptops, desktops, and printers, reducing it support tickets by 20%.

### **Technical Skills**

- Virtualization & Cloud: VMware vSphere, ESXi, Hyper-V, AWS, Azure
- Networking & Security: CCNA, FortiGate Firewalls, Sophos XG, VPNs
- ERP Systems: Odoo (Inventory, CRM, POS, Sales, Manufacturing, HR)
- System Administration: Windows Server, Active Directory, SCCM, Office 365, PowerShell
- Storage & Backup: QNAP NAS, Veeam Backup & Replication, Backup Exec
- **Development & DevOps:** SQL Server, Git, Docker, Kubernetes (In Progress)

# **Projects**

- Creating the infrastructure for two branches of networks, servers, and firewall for Sera Company.
- Installation domain, file server, ERP system for sera company.
- Create infrastructure for Abu Dhabi media corporation in Cairo office 2022.
- Improving servers and working to find the best solutions to work efficiently to increase the efficiency of the network, such as Firewall Fortinet, Qnap storage unit, and Veeam backup.
- configuration and implement Odoo ERP system 2024 for Durrat Al Rimal company.

# **Internships**

#### Udacity Nano Degree Advanced Cloud DevOps | Oct 2022 – Jan 2023

- Cloud Fundamentals
- Deploy Infrastructure as Code (IAC)
- Build CI/CD Pipelines, Monitoring and Logging

### AWS re/Start Program | May 2022 - Sep 2022

- Built fundamental IT skills, including Linux OS, writing scripts in Python and Shell
- Learned how to apply AWS services in the areas of compute, storage and networking including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lambda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53
- Learned how to configure, monitor, and support the suite of core AWS services.

# **Interpersonal Skills**

- Team Leadership
- Time Management
- Creative and Problem Solving
- Collaboration
- Adaptability

## **Certificates**

- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900)
- Advanced Cloud DevOps Udacity Nanode